<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title>Arabic Keyboard 360</title>
  <generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll v3.1.1</generator>
    <icon>http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/apple-touch-icon-precomposed.png</icon>
  <subtitle>Arabic Keyboard 360 is a website and online tool which helps type in arabic language in case you have no arabic keyboard attached to your computer </subtitle>
  <link href="http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
  <updated>2016-12-15T00:47:53+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/</uri>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title>Using the arabic keyboard Opera extension</title>
    <link href="http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/using-the-arabic-keyboard-opera-extension/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/using-the-arabic-keyboard-opera-extension</id>
    <author>
      <name></name>
      <uri>http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/</uri>
      
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      
      &lt;p&gt;In this article we are going to show how to use the Opera extension to write in Arabic letters or characters&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Using the arabic keyboard Microsoft Edge extension</title>
    <link href="http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/using-the-arabic-keyboard-microsoft-edge-extension/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/using-the-arabic-keyboard-microsoft-edge-extension</id>
    <author>
      <name></name>
      <uri>http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/</uri>
      
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      
      &lt;p&gt;Microsoft Edge is another popular browser on the web so we have made a version of our virtual keyboard as an Edge extension .In this tutorial we are going to see how to download and install the Edge extension and start using to write in Arabic letters.&lt;/p&gt;


    </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Using the arabic keyboard Firefox extension</title>
    <link href="http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/using-the-arabic-keyboard-firefox-extension/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/using-the-arabic-keyboard-firefox-extension</id>
    <author>
      <name></name>
      <uri>http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/</uri>
      
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      
      &lt;p&gt;If you are a FireFox user and loves to use addons ,our online service is also available as FireFox addon or extension which you can download and install via the Mozilla Addon Store.In this article i’m going to show you how to get ready to use our Arabic keyboard in your FireFox browser.&lt;/p&gt;


    </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Using the arabic keyboard Desktop app for Windows and Linux</title>
    <link href="http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/using-the-arabic-keyboard-desktop-app-for-windows-and-linux/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/using-the-arabic-keyboard-desktop-app-for-windows-and-linux</id>
    <author>
      <name></name>
      <uri>http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/</uri>
      
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      
      In case you don&#39;t have a permanent connexion to Internet ,you can also use our Desktop application which offers you a virtual arabic keyboard so instead of using the online service you can use the offline Desktop app .
In this tutorial i&#39;ll show you the necessary steps that you need to perform to download and install the Desktop application.so lets start .
 
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Using the arabic keyboard Chrome extension</title>
    <link href="http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/using-the-arabic-keyboard-chrome-extension/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/using-the-arabic-keyboard-chrome-extension</id>
    <author>
      <name></name>
      <uri>http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/</uri>
      
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      
      &lt;p&gt;Our arabic keyboard is also available as a chrome extension which you can download and install then start using it to type in Arabic using the English/French alphabet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial i’ll show the procedure of downloading and installing the extension from the Chrome web store.so lets get started&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>How to use the arabic keyboard ?</title>
    <link href="http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/how-to-use-the-arabic-keyboard/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/how-to-use-the-arabic-keyboard</id>
    <author>
      <name></name>
      <uri>http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/</uri>
      
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      
      &lt;p&gt;In the previous post we talked about online arabic keyboards and when people use them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post i’ll show you how you can use an online arabic keyboard .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First you need to pick up an online arabic keyboard website you can choose from many available websites such as&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;www.arabickeyboard360.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go ahead and type the address in your browser address bar&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>How to Use The Google Keyboard on Your Samsung Android Device</title>
    <link href="http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/how-to-use-the-google-keyboard-on-your-samsung-android-device/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/how-to-use-the-google-keyboard-on-your-samsung-android-device</id>
    <author>
      <name></name>
      <uri>http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/</uri>
      
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      
      &lt;p&gt;In this post i&#39;m going to show you how to use the Google Android keyboard(Created by Android team) instead of Samsung keyboard on your android device. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	This is your keyboard before replacing it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/images/samsung-keyboard.png&quot; alt=&quot;samsung android keyboard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	This is your keyboard after replacing it with official android keyboard.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/images/google-android-keyboard.png&quot; alt=&quot;google android keyboard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	So go ahead and launch your Play Store on your android device.

	Next you need to search for the official android keyboad on the Play Store,just go to the search bar and enter &quot;google keyboard&quot;.
	You&#39;ll get the link to the official keyboard on the first search result. 


&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/images/google-keyboard-play-store.png&quot; alt=&quot;google keyboard play store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Next you just need to install like any normal app
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/images/install-google-keyboard.png&quot; alt=&quot;install google keyboard play store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	After installing the Google keyboard .Now go to the home screen of your android device and look for its icon .Tap it to launch the keyboard app.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Now you need to follow a one time configuration guide.Tap on &quot;Get started&quot;. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/images/google-keyboard-get-started.png &quot; alt=&quot; google keyboard  get started play store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Next tap on enable in settings.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/images/google-keyboard-enable-settings.png&quot; alt=&quot; google keyboard  enable settings &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Now you need to enable the second keyboard
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/images/google-keyboard-settings.png &quot; alt=&quot; google keyboard settings &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Don&#39;t worry about this attention message just tap on OK.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/images/google-keyboard-attention.png &quot; alt=&quot; google keyboard attention &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Next tap switch input methods.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/images/google-keyboard-switch-input-methods.png&quot; alt=&quot;google keyboard switch input methods &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Select English (US) Google keyboard.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/images/google-keyboard-select.png&quot; alt=&quot;google keyboard select &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	This all what you need to now just launch any app that uses the keyboard to see the keyboard you&#39;ve just configured as your default keyboard for samsung android device.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/images/google-keyboard-finish.png&quot; alt=&quot;google keyboard finish &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;
	Conclusion
&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post we have seen how to switch the samsung keyboard with the official Google Android device created by Android team.&lt;/p&gt;


    </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>What is the arabic keyboard ?</title>
    <link href="http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/what-is-the-arabic-keyboard/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/what-is-the-arabic-keyboard</id>
    <author>
      <name></name>
      <uri>http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/</uri>
      
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/images/whatisarabickeyboard.png&quot; alt=&quot;what&#39;s arabic keyboard ?&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The arabic keyboard is the keyboard used by people in North Africa and Middle East countries to type in Arabic language.In the contrary of the occidental keyboards ,arabic keyboards contain both arabic and latin characters because latin letters are used to type &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uniform_Resource_Locator&quot;&gt;URLs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Email_address&quot;&gt;email addresses&lt;/a&gt;.The arabic language is written from right to left so if you are typing in arabic keyboard you are going to see characters showing up from right to left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/images/wiki-arabic-keyboard.png&quot; alt=&quot;wikipedia arabic keyboard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The online arabic keyboard is an arabic transliteratin system that transforms your keyboard typed characters to arabic equivalents so you don’t have to use a physical keyboard with arabic keys if you need to write some arabic text.These kind of virtual keyboards are used in the arabic world espeially in north africa.in these countries peope usually use latin keyboards but they need to write arabic too so such virtual keyboards become popular between people most of time in a form of a website which offers a virtual keyboard where people type latins characters and get transliterted arabic text which they can then copy and paste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-most-popular-online-arabic-keyboards&quot;&gt;The most popular online arabic keyboards&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People across the arabic world are using online and virtual arabic keyboards to type their text ,to search on search engines ,on youtube etc.. here is a list of the most popular online arabic keyboards used nowadays:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Arabic-keyboard.org&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.arabic-keyboard.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.arabic-keyboard.org&lt;/a&gt; website is one of the oldest and most used online arabic keyboard website .It is ranked as the first website in Google results for the &lt;b&gt;arabic keyboard&lt;/b&gt; keywords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the screenshot of this website&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/images/arabic-keyboard-org.png&quot; alt=&quot;arabic keyboard org&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see it has a simple interface with a virtual keyboard with arabic keys which arabic people or anyone interested in writing arabic language can use to type in Arabic letters either by using the mouse and clicking on the keyboard keys or by using english letters via the physical keyboard attached to a computer ,the website takes care of transliterating or converting the latin characters to a phonetically equivalent characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) clavier-arab.org&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.clavier-arab.org/arabic-keyboard/&quot;&gt;http://www.clavier-arab.org/arabic-keyboard/&lt;/a&gt; is another popular online arabic keyboard website which has the second rank on Google results for the same keywords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/images/clavier-arab.png&quot; alt=&quot;clavier arabe&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see you can also use this arabic keyboard tool in two ways .Either by using the mouse or your physical latin keyboard ,if you choose to use the second way letters will get transliterated automatically for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lexilogos.com/keyboard/arabic.htm&quot;&gt;lexilogos-keyboard-arabic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lexilogos arabic keyboard is the oldest one and has third rank on Google results for the same keywords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/images/lexilogos-keyboard-arabic.png&quot; alt=&quot;lexilogos keyboard arabic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also use it in the same way as the two previous &lt;b&gt;online arabic keyboards&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) clavier-arab-pro.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is another popular online tool for typing arabic in latin characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/images/clavier-arabe-pro.png&quot; alt=&quot;clavier arabe pro&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use this tool in two ways by using your mouse or your physical keyboard .You can use also to translate from arabic to many languages like English,French etc..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-to-use-arabic-keyboard-&quot;&gt;When to use arabic keyboard ?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use the arabic keyboard in many situations such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you don’t have a real physical arabic keyboard .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are a traveller and you visit countries where there are no arabic keyboards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want more security when typing your sensitive data such as passwords .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general virtual keyboards are used for ensuring security when you are online.Hackers use different techniques to steal your sensitive data such as passwords and other informations so if you even own an arabic keyboard but want more security when typing your data online you can use an arabic keyboard to type your arabic data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-use-the-arabic-keyboard-&quot;&gt;How to use the arabic keyboard ?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So first of all,find a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; with an online arabic keyboard .You can choose any website from many available websites either using the list i gave you above or you can just use Google to search for one ,Just type “arabic keyboard” !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/images/how-to-find-an-arabic-keyboard.png&quot; alt=&quot;How to find an arabic keyboard ?&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finding a good website . You have two ways to use the virtual keyboard .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Method one&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use your mouse to type the arabic characters on the virtual keyboard .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Method two&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use your physical keyboard to type in latin or English characters .Typed characters will get automatically transliterated to Arabic .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-transliteration-&quot;&gt;What is transliteration ?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transliteration is simply converting one language alphabets to their phonetically equivalents characters&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/images/alphabet.png&quot; alt=&quot;arabic alphabet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;online-vs-desktop-vs-plugin-arabic-keyboard&quot;&gt;Online vs Desktop vs plugin Arabic keyboard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we said before we can use the arabic keyboard via an online website which you can access easily using your browser by just typing the url of the website offering the keyboard but you can also use :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1)Arabic keyboard desktop app&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a small desktop application available either on Windows or Linux which you can use to type in Arabic alphabets using latin characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use it either through your mouse or via your physical keyboard.After typing what you need to type just copy your typed text and paste it wherever you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also you this desktop application to type in Arabic and search automatically in Google.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/images/arabic-keyboard-desktop.png&quot; alt=&quot;arabic keyboard desktop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2)Arabic keyboard Browser extension or addon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also use the arabic keyboard in the form of an addon either for Chrome or Firefox&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Arabic keyboard layouts</title>
    <link href="http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/arabic-keyboard-layouts/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/arabic-keyboard-layouts</id>
    <author>
      <name></name>
      <uri>http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/</uri>
      
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      
      &lt;p&gt;In this post we are going to see differents layouts used by arabic keyboards .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-arabic-keyboard&quot;&gt;The arabic keyboard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The arabic keyboard is the keyboard used to type arabic alphabets.It contains both latin and arabic because latin letters and numbers are used for different things which can not be typed in arabic such as emails or urls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;arabic-keyboard-layouts&quot;&gt;Arabic keyboard layouts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A layout is simply how characters are distributed relatively to each other.Different layouts are used by companies which make keyboards .So lets see the diffrent layouts used by arabic keyboards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;arabic-typewriter-layout&quot;&gt;Arabic typewriter layout&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is the first and oldest layout used for typewriters ,it was made by the syrian inventor Selim Shibli Haddad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a screenshot of this layout&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/images/arabiclayout1.png&quot; alt=&quot;arabic layout &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sakhrmsx-arabic-keyboard&quot;&gt;Sakhr/MSX Arabic Keyboard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/images/arabiclayout2.png&quot; alt=&quot;arabic layout &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ibm-pc-arabic-keyboard&quot;&gt;IBM PC Arabic Keyboard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/images/arabiclayout3.png&quot; alt=&quot;arabic layout&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mac-arabic-keyboard&quot;&gt;Mac Arabic Keyboard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/images/arabiclayout4.png&quot; alt=&quot;arabic layout&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;intellark-arabic-keyboard&quot;&gt;Intellark Arabic Keyboard&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.arabickeyboard360.com/images/arabiclayout5.png&quot; alt=&quot;arabic layout&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arabic_keyboard&quot;&gt;Arabic keyboard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intellark&quot;&gt;Intellark&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://oztypewriter.blogspot.ru/2014/10/the-arabic-typewriter-keyboard-and.html&quot;&gt;The arabic typewriter keyboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
</feed>